{"name": "\u65e7OG4  66F", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. On level ground, a vertical rod 12 feet tail casts a shadow 4 feet long, and at the same time a nearby vertical flagpole casts a shadow 12 feet long. How many feet tail is the flagpole?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "8", "C": "12", "D": "20", "E": "36"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. The cost of a gym membership is a onetime fee of $140\uff0cplus a monthly fee of $40. Brendan wrote a $500 check to pay his gym membership for a certain number of months, including the onetime fee. How many months of membership did he pay for?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "9", "D": "12", "E": "13"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. If x = -5, what is the value of?", "choices": {"A": "-6", "B": "-4", "C": "4", "D": "", "E": "19"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. A museum offers a 2-hour guided group tour. For groups with fewer than 25 people the cost is $9.25 per person; for groups with 25 people or more the cost is $8.50 per person. The 27 people in the 9:00 a.m. tour group each paid $9.25 in advance. What is the total refund that the museum owes the 9:00 a.m. group?", "choices": {"A": "$12.50", "B": "$13.00", "C": "$18.75", "D": "$20.25", "E": "$25.00"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. The 13-member math club needs to choose a student government representative. They decide that the representative, who will be chosen at random, CANNOT be any of the 3 officers of the club. What is the probability that Samara, who is a member of the club but NOT an officer, will be chosen?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. What is the perimeter, in centimeters, of a rectangle with length 15 cm and width 6 cm?", "choices": {"A": "21", "B": "30", "C": "42", "D": "90", "E": "180"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. Tickets for a community theater production cost $6 each when bought in advance and $8 each when bought at the door. The theater group's goal is at least $2,000 in ticket sales for opening night. The theater group sold 142 opening-night tickets in advance. What is the minimum number of tickets they need to sell at the door on opening night to make their goal?", "choices": {"A": "143", "B": "144", "C": "192", "D": "250", "E": "357"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. For what value of  r is the equation true?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "6", "C": "14", "D": "15", "E": "18"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. If 12(x - 11) = -15, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. In the figure below, A, D, C, and E are collinear. AD, BD, and BC are all the same length, and the angle measure of \u2220ABD is as marked. What is the degree measure of \u2220BCE?", "choices": {"A": "50\u00b0", "B": "100\u00b0", "C": "105\u00b0", "D": "130\u00b0", "E": "160\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. If f(x) = 9x2 + 5x - 8, then f(-2) = ?", "choices": {"A": "-54", "B": "-18", "C": " 18", "D": "36", "E": "38"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. What is the least common multiple of 30, 20, and 70 ?", "choices": {"A": "40", "B": "42", "C": "120", "D": "420", "E": "42,000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. While doing a problem on his calculator, Tom meant to divide a number by 2, but instead he accidentally multiplied the number by 2. Which of the following calculations could Tom then do to the result on the calculator screen to obtain the result he originally wanted?", "choices": {"A": "Subtract the original number", "B": "Multiply by 2", "C": "Multiply by 4", "D": "Divide by 2", "E": "Divide by 4"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. The 8-sided figure below is divided into 5 congruent squares. The total area of the 5 squares is 125 square inches. What is the perimeter, in inches, of the figure ?", "choices": {"A": "25", "B": "60", "C": "80", "D": "100", "E": "125"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. In \u25b3ABC, \u2220A measures greater than 43\u00b0 and \u2220B measures exactly 90\u00b0. Which of the following phrases best describes the measure of \u2220C ?", "choices": {"A": "Greater than 47\u00b0", "B": "Equal to 47\u00b0", "C": "Equal to 60\u00b0", "D": "Equal to 133\u00b0", "E": "Less than 47\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. Among the following arithmetic operations, which could the symbol \u2662 represent given that the equation (2 \u2662 1)4 + (6 \u2662 3)2 = 10 is true?        I. Addition       II. Subtraction      III. Division", "choices": {"A": "I only", "B": "II only", "C": "\u2162 only", "D": "I and II only", "E": "I, II, and III"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. One of the following is an equation of the linear relation shown in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below.  Which equation is it?", "choices": {"A": "y = 5x", "B": "y = 2x", "C": "y = 5x + 2", "D": "y = 2x - 5", "E": "y = 2x + 5"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. An integer, n, is added to 4. That sum is then multiplied by 8. This result is 10 less than twice the original integer. Which of the following equations represents this relationship ?", "choices": {"A": "8(n + 4) = 2n - 10", "B": "8(n + 4) - 10 = 2n", "C": "8(n + 4) = 10 - 2n", "D": " n + 4 \u00d7 8 = 2n - 10", "E": "4 + 8 = 2n - 10"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. Two workers were hired to begin work at the same time. Worker A\u2019s contract called for a starting salary of $20,000 with an increase of $800 after each year of employment. Worker B\u2019s contract called for a starting salary of $15,200 with an increase of $2,000 after each year of employment. If x represents the number of full years\u2019 employment (that is, the number of yearly increases each worker has received), which of the following equations could be solved to determine the number of years until B\u2019s yearly salary equals A\u2019s yearly salary?", "choices": {"A": "20,000 + 800x = 15,200 + 2,000x", "B": "20,000 + 2,000x = 15,200 + 800x", "C": "(20,000 + 800)x = (15,200 + 2,000)x", "D": "(2,000 + 800)x = 20,000 - 15,200", "E": "(2,000 - 800)x = 20,000 + 15,200"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. A ramp for loading trucks is 13 feet long and covers 12 feet along the level ground, as shown below. How many feet high is the highest point on the ramp ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. The expression 7(x + 3) - 3(2x - 2) is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "x + 1", "B": "x + 15", "C": "x + 19", "D": "x + 23", "E": "x + 27"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. If x + y = 32, and x - y = 12, then y = ?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "10", "C": "20", "D": "22", "E": "44"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. When (2x - 3)2 is written in the form ax2+ bx + c, where a, b, and c are integers, a + b + c = ?", "choices": {"A": "-17", "B": "-5", "C": "1", "D": "13", "E": "25"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. What is the area, in square feet, of the figure below ?", "choices": {"A": "60", "B": "80", "C": "275", "D": "375", "E": "450"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. The table below gives the values of 2 functions, f and g, for various values of x. One of the functions expresses a linear relationship. What is the value of that function at x = 4 ?", "choices": {"A": "0.2", "B": "0.4", "C": "1.9", "D": "2.0", "E": "2.2"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. What is the slope of the line represented by the equation 6y - 14x = 5 ?", "choices": {"A": "-14", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "6", "E": "14"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. What is the sum of the 2 solutions of the equation x2 + x - 12 = 0 ?", "choices": {"A": "-12", "B": "-4", "C": "-1", "D": "0", "E": "3"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Two similar triangles have perimeters in the ratio 3:5. The sides of the smaller triangle measure 3 cm, 5 cm, and 7 cm, respectively. What is the perimeter, in centimeters, of the larger triangle ?", "choices": {"A": "15", "B": "18", "C": "20", "D": "25", "E": "36"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. At a certain location, the low temperatures, in degrees Fahrenheit, for each of 7 consecutive days in January were -2\u00b0F, 4\u00b0F, -3\u00b0F, 1\u00b0F, 2\u00b0F, -5\u00b0F, and -6\u00b0F. What was the median of these low temperatures?", "choices": {"A": "-2\u00b0F", "B": "-1\u00b0F", "C": "1\u00b0F", "D": "3\u00b0F", "E": "4\u00b0F"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. When asked his age, the algebra teacher said, \u201cIf you square my age, then subtract 23 times my age, the result is 50.\u201d  How old is he ?", "choices": {"A": "23", "B": "25", "C": "27", "D": "46", "E": "50"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. The distance, d, an accelerating object travels in t seconds can be modeled by the equation, where a is the acceleration rate, in meters per second per second. If a car accelerates from a stop at the rate of 20 meters per second per second and travels a distance of 80 meters, about how many seconds did the car travel ?", "choices": {"A": "Between 1 and 2", "B": "Between 2 and 3", "C": "Between 3 and 4", "D": "4", "E": "8"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Let a, b, c, and d be distinct positive integers. What is the 4th term of the geometric sequence below?bcd, abc2d, a2bc3d, \u2026", "choices": {"A": "a3bc4d", "B": "a3b2c3d", "C": "a3b2c4d2", "D": "a4bc6d", "E": "a4bc9d"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. Use the following information to answer questions 33-35.A survey in a study skills class asked the 20 students enrolled in the class how many hours (rounded to the nearest hour) they had spent studying on the previous evening. The 20 responses are summarized by the histogram below.33. What fraction of the students responded that they had spent less than 3 hours studying?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. Use the following information to answer questions 33-35.A survey in a study skills class asked the 20 students enrolled in the class how many hours (rounded to the nearest hour) they had spent studying on the previous evening. The 20 responses are summarized by the histogram below.34. The teacher decides to show the data in a circle graph (pie chart). What should be the measure of the central angle of the sector for 3 hours ?", "choices": {"A": " 18\u00b0", "B": " 20\u00b0", "C": " 36\u00b0", "D": " 72\u00b0", "E": " 90\u00b0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. Use the following information to answer questions 33-35.A survey in a study skills class asked the 20 students enrolled in the class how many hours (rounded to the nearest hour) they had spent studying on the previous evening. The 20 responses are summarized by the histogram below.35. To the nearest tenth of an hour, what is the average number of hours for the 20 survey responses ?", "choices": {"A": " 2.0", "B": " 2.1", "C": " 2.3", "D": " 2.5", "E": " 3.0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. For all x \uff1e21,  = ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. The bottom of the basket of a hot-air balloon is parallel to the level ground. One taut tether line 144 feet long is attached to the center of the bottom of the basket and is anchored to the ground at an angle of 72\u00b0, as shown in the figure below. Which of the following expressions gives the distance, in feet, from the center of the bottom of the basket to the ground ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "144 tan 72\u00b0", "D": "144 cos 72\u00b0", "E": "144 sin 72\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. The coordinates of the endpoints of GH, in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, are (-8,-3) and (2, 3). What is the x-coordinate of the midpoint of GH ?", "choices": {"A": "-6", "B": "-3", "C": "0", "D": "3", "E": "5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. On a map in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, the towns of Arlington and Betelwood are represented by the points (-2,-3) and (-6,-7), respectively. Each unit on the map represents an actual distance of 10 miles. Which of the following is closest to the distance, in miles, between these 2 towns ?", "choices": {"A": "128", "B": "57", "C": "42", "D": "40", "E": "28"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. Which of the following statements is true about rational and/or irrational numbers?", "choices": {"A": "The product of any 2 irrational numbers is irrational.", "B": "The quotient of any 2 irrational numbers is rational.", "C": "The product of any 2 rational numbers is irrational.", "D": "The quotient of any 2 rational numbers is irrational.", "E": "The sum of any 2 rational numbbrs is rational."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. For the complex number i and an integer x, which of the following is a possible value of ix ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "3", "E": "4"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Consider the equation y = (x - 3)2 + 2 where x and y are both real numbers. The table below gives the values of y for selected values of x.For the equation above, which of the following values of x gives the least value of y ?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. The height and radius of the right circular cylinder below are given in meters. What is the volume, in cubic meters, of the cylinder ?", "choices": {"A": "30\u03c0", "B": "31\u03c0", "C": "150\u03c0", "D": "180\u03c0", "E": "900\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Lines l1 and l2 intersect each other and 3 parallel lines, l3, l4, and l5, at the points shown in the figure below. The ratio of the perimeter of \u25b3ABC to the perimeter of \u25b3AFG is 1:3. The ratio of DE to FG is 2 : 3. What is the ratio of AC to CE ?", "choices": {"A": "1 : 1", "B": "1 : 2", "C": "1 : 3", "D": "2 : 1", "E": "3 : 1"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. A rocket lifted off from a launch pad arid traveled vertically 30 kilometers, then traveled 40 kilometers at 30\u00b0 from the veitical, and then traveled 100 kilometers at 45\u00b0 from the vertical, as shown in the figure below. At that point, the rocket was how many kilometers above the height of the launch pad ?", "choices": {"A": "100", "B": "170", "C": "190", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the area of the circle x2 +y2 = 16 ?", "choices": {"A": "4\u03c0", "B": "8\u03c0", "C": "16\u03c0", "D": "64\u03c0", "E": "256\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below, 1 side of a rectangle is on the x-axis, and the vertices of the opposite side of the rectangle are on the graph of the parabola y = 6 - 2x2. Let a represent any value of x such that 0 &lt; x &lt; . Which of the following is an expression in terms of a for the area, in square coordinate units, of any such rectangle ?", "choices": {"A": "-4a3 + 12a", "B": "-2a3 + 6a", "C": "-4a2 + 4a + 12", "D": "-2a2 + 2a + 6", "E": "4a4 - 24a2 + 36"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. If n is a positive integer, which of the following expressions must be an odd integer ?", "choices": {"A": "3n", "B": "n3", "C": "3n", "D": "", "E": "3 + n"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. The value of   is between which of the following pairs of consecutive integers ?", "choices": {"A": "0 and 1", "B": "4 and 5", "C": "5 and 6", "D": "6 and 7", "E": "9 and 10"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Use the following information to answer questions 50-52.The table below shows the weekly sales totals (in thousands of dollars) for 4 departments at Pinky\u2019s Megamarket during the 5 most recent weeks. Data is missing due to a computer virus that infected the supermarket\u2019s database. The data in the table has been verified as being accurate.50. Which of the following is closest to the percent increase in meat department sales for Pinky\u2019s Megamarket from Week 2 to Week 3 ?", "choices": {"A": "1.1%", "B": "6.0%", "C": "7.7%", "D": "8.3%", "E": "12.0%"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Use the following information to answer questions 50-52.The table below shows the weekly sales totals (in thousands of dollars) for 4 departments at Pinky\u2019s Megamarket during the 5 most recent weeks. Data is missing due to a computer virus that infected the supermarket\u2019s database. The data in the table has been verified as being accurate.51. Prior to Week 3, the manager set the goal for meat department sales to average 150 thousand dollars per week from the beginning of Week 3 through the end of Week 6. To meet this goal, what must be the minimum meat department sales for Week 6, in thousands of dollars ?", "choices": {"A": " 146", "B": "147", "C": " 156", "D": " 159", "E": " 170"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Use the following information to answer questions 50-52.The table below shows the weekly sales totals (in thousands of dollars) for 4 departments at Pinky\u2019s Megamarket during the 5 most recent weeks. Data is missing due to a computer virus that infected the supermarket\u2019s database. The data in the table has been verified as being accurate.52. The assistant manager recalls that produce department sales increased at a very high rate during the 5 weeks, due to a projected shortage of fruit. She says that for each week from Week 2 to Week 5, produce department sales increased 10% from the previous week. Which of the following values, in thousands of dollars, is closest to produce department sales for Week 5 ?", "choices": {"A": "48", "B": " 44", "C": " 42", "D": " 40", "E": " 33"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. A trigonometric function with equation y = a sin(bx + c), where a, b, and c are real numbers, is graphed in the standard (x, y) coordinate plane below. The period of this function f(x) is the smallest positive number p such that f(x + p) = f(x) for every real number x. One of the following is the period of this function. Which one is it ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "\u03c0", "C": "2\u03c0", "D": "4\u03c0", "E": "2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. The building below casts a shadow 24 yards long, and the angle of elevation from the tip of the shadow to the top of the building has a sine of . What is the height of the building in yards ?", "choices": {"A": "14.4", "B": "18.0", "C": "19.2", "D": "30.0", "E": "32.0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. Which of the following is an irrational number that is a solution to the equation ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. The graph below shows the distance Malika is from a motion detector for a period of 10 seconds. A certain order of 3 of the following 5 actions describes Malika\u2019s movement in relation to the position of the motion detector. Which order is it ?         I. Stands still for 5 seconds        II. Walks away at 4 feet per second        III. Walks toward at 4 feet per second       IV. Walks away at 2 feet per second        V. Walks toward at 2 feet per second", "choices": {"A": "\u2160, \u2161, \u2164", "B": "\u2161, \u2160, \u2164", "C": "\u2162, \u2160, \u2163", "D": "\u2163, \u2160, \u2162", "E": "\u2164, \u2160, \u2161"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. As shown in the figure below, a clock has a minute hand that measures 5 cm from its tip to the center of the clock. To the nearest centimeter, what is the distance traveled by the tip of the minute hand between 2:10 p.m. and 5:30 p.m. ?", "choices": {"A": "31", "B": "68", "C": "101", "D": "105", "E": "173"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. For \u03c6, an angle whose measure is between 90\u00b0 and 180\u00b0, tan \u03c6 = . Which of the following equals sin \u03c6\uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. Consider all pairs of positive integers w and z whose sum is 5. For how many values of w does there exist a positive integer x that satisfies both 2w = x and xx = 64 ?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "8", "E": "Infinitely many"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. A cube with edges 4 cm long is inscribed in a sphere, as shown below. What is the radius of the sphere, in centimeters ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "2"}, "correct": "A"}]}